# JESULOBA JOHN ABERE

jesulobajohn@gmail.com ♦ +234 703 186 4774 ♦ Github ♦ LinkedIn ♦ Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

Forward-thinking Software Engineer with a good understanding of techniques geared towards optimum user experience. Skilled in solving problems with Javascript, Typescript, React, Node.js and Django. Proud team player focused on achieving project objectives with speed and accuracy.

# **SKILLS**

Languages
Technologies

Javascript, Typescript, Python, C++, Java

 $React,\,Next.js,\,React-Native,\,Redux,\,Zustand,\,Mobx,\,Graphql,\,Git,\,Django,\,Node.js,\,Express,\,React,$ 

Cypress, Heroku, Solidity, Tailwind, AWS, styled-components, Docker, React-query, Jest

#### EXPERIENCE

# Software Engineer

Aug 2022 - present

Sidebrief

- Collaborated with product managers and designers to create wireframes, mockups, and prototypes for new web applications, resulting in a 40% decrease in development time.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to identify and address key performance bottlenecks, resulting in a 30% improvement in page load times.
- Developed robust, scalable, modular and API-centric infrastructures that resulted in a decrease of customer complaints by 30%.
- Successfully recommended UI technologies and processes to ensure the versatility and quality of our user interfaces.

#### Front-end Developer

Sept 2020 - Aug 2022

Maze-softwares

- Analyzed customer behavior to identify areas of improvement in the user experience, proposed solutions that increased customer satisfaction by 15%.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to streamline process and improve communication, resulting in a 10% increase in efficiency.
- Implemented responsive design principles into all web applications, optimizing mobile user experiences and increasing mobile traffic by 50%.
- Collaborated with UX designers and product managers to ensure creative proposals aligned with design best practices and stakeholder expectations.

### Software Engineering Intern

Feb 2020 - Sept 2020

Needle inc.

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to integrate third-party APIs into existing systems, resulting in a 50% reduction in manual data entry errors.
- Revamped CSS structure, reducing load time by 40% and improving user experience for the visitors.
- Developed and implemented a suite of APIs using Python/Django, resulting in a 30% reduction in overall system latency and increasing API uptime by 15%.

# **EDUCATION**